Mss.974.811.Ea7
American Philosophical Society
Eastwick Collection, 1746-1929
Mss.974.811.Ea7
American Philosophical Society
2.0 Linear feet Ca. 1500 items
Ca. 1500 items.
This collection includes letters, diaries, notebooks, and early photographs, relating primarily to the Wister family of Germantown and Philadelphia. Much of the correspondence concerns domestic news and consists of letters from or to Sarah Wister. These include interesting observations on Germantown and Philadelphia society from other families as well, such as the Bayntons and Bullocks. There are numerous letters from various Wisters, including Casper, Charles Jones, Elizabeth (including a journal of a trip to Bristol, 1783), Hannah, John, Owen Jones, and others. There is also poetry by Sarah.
Wistar family.
Box 1-4
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Joseph L. Eastwick and Suzanne Wister and accessioned, 07/02/1975 (1975 784ms, 785ms).
General note
The Wister family of Philadelphia is related to the Wistar family of the same city through the brothers Caspar (1696-1752) and John Wüster (1708-1789), the former taking "Wistar" and the latter, "Wister." See John W. Jordan, "Colonial and Revolutionary Families of Pennsylvania" (NY: Lewis Publising Co., 1911).
Early American History Note
This large and rich collection contains a range of documents including travel journals, diaries, business records, and personal correspondence. The largest portion of the collection is of correspondence among members of the extended Wister family and their network of friends in the early nineteenth century, which provides insight into early nineteenth century Germantown and Philadelphia culture and society. These often long letters lend insight into all aspect of nineteenth century life, including politics, courtship, friendship, family, and manners. Poetry of Elizabeth, Sarah, and Charles Wister is included, as are daybooks and journals of Sarah.
Aside from the Wister family correspondence in the collection, the Eastwick collection contains a variety of bound volumes that deal with the Wister family’s business affairs, agricultural interests, and travel in the nineteenth century. All totaled, there are over twenty bound volumes (journals, diaries, account books) in the collection. The collection contains a travel journal to Bristol, Pennsylvania in 1783, to Pittsburgh in 1812, to Niagara Falls in 1815, a bee book and a farm book from the nineteenth century, a garden book from the eighteenth century, and assorted diaries, memoranda books, journals, and account books (often of Charles Wister). Included in the bound portion of the collection is a journal of a love affair kept by Elizabeth Wister.
Among the diaries are records of Jesse and John Lukens, Pennsylvania surveyors who were also involved in the dispute with the Susquehanna Company in northern Pennsylvania. Also of note in the collection is a series of letters and other documents relating to the administration of the United States Lottery held during the American Revolution.
The collection also contains extremely rare early Daguerre photographs taken in the 1840s. The photographs are of homes, including Grumblethorpe (the Wister family home) and the Philadelphia observatory.
Bayntun family.; Bullock family.; Darlington, William, 1782-1863; Lukens, Jesse; Lukens, John, 1720-1789; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865; Wister, Charles Jones,1822-1910.; Wister, Daniel, 1739-1805; Wister, Elizabeth, 1764-1812; Wister, Hannah, 1767-1827; Wister, John, -- 1776-1862.; Wister, Owen J., (Owen Jones), 1825-1896; Wister, Sarah, 1761-1804; Agriculture -- United States.; American Revolution; Bees.; Business and Skilled Trades; Daybooks.; Diaries; Diaries.; England -- Description and travel.; Family Correspondence; Gardening -- United States.; General Correspondence; Germantown (Philadelphia, Pa.) -- Social life and customs.; Land and Speculation; Literature; Literature, Arts, and Culture; Maps and Surveys; Marriage and Family Life; Niagara Falls (N.Y.); Notebooks.; Philadelphia (Pa.) -- Social life and customs.; Photoprints.; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Description and travel.; Poems.; Social Life and Custom; Surveying and Maps; Travel Narratives and Journals; Women's History
- Papers
  - ALS to Charles Wister, March 1845; 1.0 p.; Abert, John James, 1788-1863
  - ALS to Charles J. Wister, 6 December 1844; 3.0 p. Contains 2 tables of contents of proceedings at the American Philosophical Society.; American Philosophical Society.
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 12 January; 3.0 p.; Anna
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 21 January; 3.0 p.; Anna
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 10 July; 4.0 p.; Anna
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 16 May 1803; 3.0 p.; Bayard, Anna Maria
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 6 July 1787; 4.0 p.; Bayard, Samuel
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 6 September 1794; 2.0 p.; Bayard, Samuel
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 25 January 1795; 7.0 p.; Bayard, Samuel
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wistar, 8 October; 3.0 p.; Bayard, Samuel
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 5 April 1805; 2.0 p.; Baynton, Catherine
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 22 January 1805; 2.0 p.; Baynton, Catherine
  - ALS to Mrs. Wister, 3 March 1805; 2.0 p.; Baynton, Catherine
  - ALS to Mrs. Wister, 17 March 1804; 2.0 p.; Baynton, Catherine
  - ALS to Mr. Bullock, 25 October 1788; 1.0 p.; Baynton, Peter
  - ALS to Mrs. Esther Bullock, June; 2.0 p.; Baynton, Susan
    Date
    The date of this letter is hard to determine. The letter is dated "June 79 194". It may be possible that the date is 9 June 1794, but it is unclear.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 9 September 1845; 1.0 p.; Bedford, Sarah
    Recipient of letter
    This letter is addressed to Charles Wistar, however, the contents of the letter appear to be addressed to "Maurice". This may suggest that the letter was addressed to the home of Charles Wistar, but was intended for a resident of that house.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 12 September 1828; 3.0 p.; Beitel, Christian F.
  - Ballad by Swingfelter, Doctor Stuffel, 1.0 p.; Bensell, Dr. George
    Author
    The name "Stuffel Swingfelter" is probably a pen name of Dr. George Bensell.
  - Poetry by Bensell, Dr. George, 9 April 1814; 3.0 p.
  - Poetry by Bensell, Dr. George, January 1821; 3.0 p.
  - Poetry by Bensell, Dr. George, 7 January 1809; 2.0 p.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 28 July 1816; 2.0 p.; Bensell, Dr. George
  - Illustration of Bensell, George Dr., undated; 1.0 p.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 15 February 1808; 1.0 p.; Bensell, Dr. George
  - ALS to Haniel Whitesides, 8 October 1844; 1.0 p.; Bethune, M
  - Receipt to Charles Wister, 2 January 1865; 1.0 p.; Bockius, A.R. Jr.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 25 February 1835; 2.0 p.; Bohman, A
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 16 February 1833; 4.0 p. Contains one letter and an envelope from a different letter with no contents.; Bradford, Vincent
  - Bankrupt Notice to J.F. Kirkpatrick, 10 February 1843; 1.0 p.; Brown, Elyaeh
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 13 August 1815; 2.0 p.; Bullock, Anna Maria
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 13 August 1815; 3.0 p.; Bullock, Elizabeth
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 30 January 1806; 1.0 p.; Bullock, Ester Baynton
  - ALS to Miss Bullock, 28 April 1800; 2.0 p.; Bullock, Rebecca
  - ALS to Miss Bullock, 26 May 1800; 1.0 p.; Bullock, Rebecca
  - ALS to Charles Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Bullock, Sarah (Sophie)
  - ALS to William W. Wister, March 21; 2.0 p.; Bullock, Sarah (Sophie)
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 13 August 1815; 2.0 p.; Bullock, Sarah (Sophie)
  - ALS to Charles Wister, undated; 8.0 p.; Butler, Francis
    Physical Description
    This letter is composed of three parts. There is an envelope, and two seperate pieces of paper. The pieces of paper are folded to create 4 sides each.
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, undated; 1.0 p. fragment; Cathrale, Hannah
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 19 January 1825; 3.0 p.; Cathrale, Cecilia
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 18 February 1825; 2.0 p.; Cathrale, Cecilia
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 15 March 1825; 3.0 p.; Cathrale, Cecilia
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 27 March 1825; 3.0 p.; Cathrale, Cecilia
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 11 May 1825; 3.0 p.; Cathrale, Cecilia
  - ALS to Alexander Wilson, 20 November 1844; 3.0 p.; Clibborn, Joshua
  - ALS to Alexander Wilson, 9 September 1845; 1.0 p.; Clibborn, Joshua
  - ALS to Alexander Wilson, 5 March 1836; 2.0 p.; Clibborn, Joshua
  - ALS to Jesse Lickens, 11 November 1773; 4.0 p.; Connor, Morgan
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 11 January 1806; 3.0 p.; Darlington, William, 1781-1863
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 1805; 2.0 p.; Darlington, William, 1781-1863
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 1806; 2.0 p.; Darlington, William, 1781-1863
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 1806; 2.0 p.; Darlington, William, 1781-1863
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 27 June 1850; 1.0 p.; Darlington, William, 1781-1863
  - Landsale Eply, Andrew to Eggee, George and Michael, 11 April 1777; 2.0 p.
  - Envelops, Stamps & Cancellations I
  - Envelops, Stamps & Cancellations II
  - Envelops, Stamps & Cancellations III
  - Envelops, Stamps & Cancellations IV
  - Extracts of Eusebius Caevarea, 16.0 p.
  - ALS to George Bullock, 9 July 1793; 2.0 p.; Ewing, Sam
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 8 August 1830; 4.0 p.; Fahnestock, K
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 20 March 1830; 2.0 p.; Fahnestock, K
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 25 October 1815; 3.0 p.; Fayhone, Joseph
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 29 March 1776; 1.0 p.; Fishborne, Polly
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Fishborne, Polly
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 3.0 p. Highly fragmented; Fishborne, Polly
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 20 March 1795; 5.0 p. Contains 2 seperate pieces; Fisher, Edward
  - ALS to Mr's Johnson and Wister, 22 August 1841; 2.0 p.; Ford, James R.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 29 December 1807; 3.0 p. Contains two seperate pieces.; Foulke, Susan
    Location of Author
    This letter was sent from North Wales.
  - ALS to Rebecca Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Foulke, Susan
  - ALS to Rebecca Wister, undated; 2.0 p.; Foulke, Susan
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 25 November 1839; 2.0 p.; Gardner, Robert
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 14 October 1828; 3.0 p.; Gardner, Robert
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 10 June 1839; 2.0 p.; Gardner, Robert
  - Genealogical Materials, undated; 5.0 p.
  - Genealogical Materials & Information I, undated; 10.0 p.; Wister, James W.
  - Genealogical Materials & Information II, undated; 55.0 p.; Wister, James W.
  - Genealogical Materials & Information III, undated; 12.0 p.; Wister, James W.
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 16 March 1778; 1.0 p. Fragmented into two pieces.; Gibson, John
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 12 February 1778; 1.0 p.; Gibson, John
  - ALS to Samuel Shoch, 6 July 1854; 1.0 p.; Girard Bank.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, October 1841; 4.0 p.; Green, Dr.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 4 September 1795; 3.0 p.; Griffitts, Mary
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 15 October 1799; 2.0 p.; Griffitts, Mary
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 8 July 1799; 3.0 p.; Griffitts, Mary
  - ALS to George Warren, 3 August 1817; 1.0 p.; Hankinson, John
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 20 July 1845; 3.0 p.; Hankinson, Harry
  - Passport of Heutzeberg, Johan Carl, 1764; 1.0 p.
  - Will of Heuzeberg, Charles, 1793; 2.0 p.
  - ALS to John Price, 1 February 1828; 3.0 p.; Higgenbotham, David
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 12 November 1778; 1.0 p.; Hosmer, Titus
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 16 August 1777; 1.0 p.; Hosmer, Titus
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 3 December 1835; 1.0 p. Fragment; Howell, Joshua B.
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 1 May 1825; 3.0 p.; Howell, H.
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 12 January; 3.0 p.; Howell, H.
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 1 June 1824; 4.0 p.; Howell, H.
  - ALS to Ann Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Howell, H.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 17 January 1839; 1.0 p.; Irving, James
  - ALS to David Bernard, 2 December 1839; 1.0 p.; Jay, William
  - APcS to Charles Wister Jr., 14 May 1877; 1.0 p.; Jones, Horatio Gates
  - ALS to Charles Wister Jr., 1 December 1844; 3.0 p.; Johnson, Anthony M.
  - ALS to David Jackson, 1 June 1777; 1.0 p.; Johnston, Robert
  - ADS by Jones, Owen, 1 June 1798; 1.0 p. Possible fragment; Jones, Owen
  - ALS to David Lenox, 24 August 1791; 1.0 p.; Kidd, William
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 11 June 1792; 3.0 p.; Kirkpatrick, Jane
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 20 May 1791; 3.0 p.; Kirkpatrick, Jane
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 1 February 1790; 2.0 p.; Kirkpatrick, Jane
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 30 August 1782; 3.0 p.; Kirkpatrick, Jane
    The date of the year of this letter is uncertain.
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 15 March 1804; 3.0 p.; Kirkpatrick, Jane
  - ALS to Hannah Wister, 14 June 1812; 3.0 p.; Kirkpatrick, Jane
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 23 January 1825; 3.0 p.; L, Ann
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 20 February 1825; 4.0 p.; L, Ann
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 30 December 1824; 3.0 p.; L, Ann
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 15 November 1842; 4.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 23 May 1845; 3.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 20 January 1846; 4.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 17 August; 3.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 18 May 1844; 4.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 26 February 1845; 4.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 27 September 1845; 3.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 26 May 1846; 3.0 p.; Latimer, Sarah G.
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 3 May 1780; 1.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 23 February 1781; 2.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 17 December 1779; 1.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 1 May 1777; 1.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 22 January 1779; 1.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 28 July 1777; 1.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 20 March 1778; 1.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 19 July 1780; 1.0 p.; Lawrence, Roderic
  - Notarial Testimony, 1763; Folder empty (see also reference); Lehman, Christian
    Origin
    London Gazette
  - ALS to George Washington, 28 February 1795; 2.0 p.; Lenox, David. Philadelphia
  - ALS to Sharp Delany, 12 August 1777; 1.0 p.; Lewis, Fielding
  - Royal Proclamation, October 1763; 5.0 p.; George III, King of Great Britain, 1738-1820
  - Deed from Long, Andrew to Lukens, John, 10 November 1772; 1.0 p.
    Signers
    Signed by John Lukens, William Scull, Peter Lukens, Andrew Long, and William Plunkel.
  - Lottery Tickets & List, 11 August 1777; 29.0 p. Contains lottery tickets of the United States Lottery
    Signatures of Owen Biddle, J. Searle, J. Burge.
  - ALS to Joseph Bullock & John Mease, 24 December 1778; 1.0 p.; Loudon, Samuel
  - ALS to John Lukens, 31 July 1783; 1.0 p.; Lukens, Charles
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 13 January 1827; 3.0 p.; Lukens, Isaiah
  - ALS to General John Armstrong, 23 October 1783; 2.0 p.; Lukens, John, 1720-1789
  - Bill of Sale from Miercken, Henry to Miercken, Catherine, 2 March 1779; 3.0 p.; Miercken, Henry
  - Miercken, Peter and Morris, Samuel, a business agreement, 2 July 1783; 2.0 p. Folder empty (see also reference)
  - ALS to Lowrey Wister, 29 June 1774; 3.0 p.; Miller, Peter
    Address
    This letter was addressed to David Wister, but written by Lowrey Wister.
  - ALS to Joseph Bullock, 1787; 2.0 p.; Morgan, George, 1743-1810
  - Agreement with Peter Miercken, 22 July 1783; Morris, Samuel
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 25 July 1845; 3.0 p.; Morrison, J. William
  - ALS to Elizabeth Wister, 12 February 1815; 1.0 p.; Nancarrow, Susan Jones
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 28 November 1827; 1.0 p.; Nancarrow, Susan Jones
  - Poem by Neale Cornelius, undated; 1.0 p.
    Signature
    This document is signed W.W. Wister. (William W. Wister)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1778-16 July 1937; 9.0 p. Four pieces are contained in an oversize folder and one small piece is contained in a standard folder.
    Dates and Titles of Newspaper Clippings
    -"One Hundred Dollar Reward" 1778 -"Hints to Lecturers" 1818 -"'Lottery Mania' Once Aid to U.S." 2 April 1926 -"Girard's Talk of the Day" 16 July 1937 -(small extract on United States postal system) undated
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, undated; 3.0 p.; Norris, Deborah
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 27 February 1779; 4.0 p.; Norris, Deborah
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 27 January 1777; 3.0 p.; Norris, Deborah
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 3 May 1779; 2.0 p.; Palfray, William
  - ALS to John Morton, 15 March 1811; Pennock, William
    Name of Recipient
    The name of the recipient is hard to make out because of a rip across the written name.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 23 December 1810; 3.0 p. Fragmented into two pieces.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
  - Pharmacist's Account, 1767; 2.0 p.
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 13 November 1778; 1.0 p.; Pierce, John Jr.
  - ALS to William Wister, 4 October 1787; 3.0 p.; Pigou, Frederick
    Copy
    This document is a copy of a letter.
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 7 March; 2.0 p.; Pleasant, Nancy [?]
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 7 March 1789; 3.0 p.; Potts, Maria
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 5 June 1789; 4.0 p.; Potts, Maria
  - ALS to the President of the Board of Managers of the United States Lottery, 20 May 1779; 1.0 p.; Powell, Jeremiah
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 6 May 1778; 1.0 p.; Powell, Jeremiah
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 27 May 1828; 2.0 p.; Poice, C.M.
  - ALS to Jacob Barge, 27 May 1777; 1.0 p.; Purviance, Samuel Jr.
  - ALS to Sharpe Delany, 26 July 1780; 1.0 p.; Purviance, Samuel Jr.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 2 August 1850; 1.0 p.; Rawke, Charles
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 25 February 1839; 1.0 p.; Rawke, Charles
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 11 August; 3.0 p.; Rawle, M
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 28 July 1776; 3.0 p.; Rawle, Peggy
  - ALS to Sally (Sarah) Wister, 7 September 1776; 2.0 p.; Rawle, Peggy
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 30 May 1837; 2.0 p.; Rawle, William, 1759-1836
  - ALS to [?] B. Woolman, 3 March 1848; 1.0 p.; Remington, William
  - Business Agreement between Reser, Barnard and Wister, John, August 1746; 2.0 p.
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 18 September 1849; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    The address on this letter is interesting. Dr. Owen J. Wister was serving in the U.S. Navy aboard the U.S.S. Plymouth. The ship was serving in the East Indies and the letter was sent by Ruschenbeyer to Hong Kong for pick up by the ship.
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 29 April 1850; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 1 April 1850; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 31 December 1849; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 4 March; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 18 February 1844; 3.0 p.; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    This letter was written from a U.S. Naval Hospital in New York.
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 2 February 1845; 4.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 1 March; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 18 October 1826; 3.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - ALS to Sarah Wister, 18 December 1844; 3.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 29 September 1844; 4.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - ALS to Sallie (Sarah) Wister, 10 November 1844; 4.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 5 October 1826; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - Mrs. Charles Wister, 26 July 1844; 2.0 p.; Ruschenberger, Mary Baynton Wister
  - ALS to Madame Venue, 10 May 1808; 2.0 p.; Samson, Elizabeth
  - ALS to Miss Wister, 11 December; 7.0 p.; Sheepshanks, William
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 28 September 1826; 1.0 p.; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 3 March 1818; 2.0 p.; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    Contents
    Autographed prospects for the American Scientific Journal
  - ALS to David Jackson, 14 June 1777; 1.0 p.; Smith, Hewes J.
  - ALS to David Lenox, 13 July 1791; 1.0 p.; Wallis, Joseph
  - ALS to Miss Bullock, 4 November 1803; 2.0 p.; Watmough, Maria Ellis
  - ALS to Miss Bullock, 11 October; 1.0 p.; Watmough, Maria Ellis
  - ALS to Miss Bullock, 26 September; 2.0 p.; Watmough, Maria Ellis
  - ALS to Managers of the United States Lottery, 20 June 1777; 1.0 p.; Webb, George
  - Bill to J. Goodfellow, 1 March 1865; 1.0 p.; Weiss, Charles
  - Bill to Charles Wister, 1 April 1869; 1.0 p.; Weiss, Charles
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 26 July 1830; 3.0 p.; Wernet, Francis A.
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 4 September 1844; 3.0 p.; Whitesides, Harriett
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 8 May 1854; 4.0 p.; Whitesides, Mary
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 14 December 1835; 3.0 p.; Whitesides, Rev. Henry
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 29 January 1836; 3.0 p. Fragment; Whitesides, Rev. Henry
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 30 January 1843; 4.0 p.; Whitesides, Rev. Henry
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 10 August 1848; 3.0 p.; Whitesides, Rev. Henry
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 24 May 1842; 4.0 p.; Whitesides, Rev. Henry
  - ALS to Sharpe Delany, 28 July 1777; 1.0 p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
  - ALS to William Wilson, 24 May 1815; 4.0 p.; Wilson, Margaret
  - ALS to Alexander Wilson, 14 September 1843; 2.0 p.; Wilson, Rev. R.
  - Winchester, Eliza indentured to Bullock, Mary, 12 April 1825; 1.0 p.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 26 May 1840; 1.0 p.; Winebrener, R.W.
  - ALS to Ann Wister, 19 October 1835; 4.0 p.
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 18 July 1834; 2.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 19 July 1835; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 22 May 1835; 1.0 p. fragment; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 19 January 1835; 2.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 22 March 1840; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 13 February 1835; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 17 June 1840; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 28 December 1839; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 9 December 1841; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 20 December 1840; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 24 September 1834; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Charles Wister, 17 April 1842; 3.0 p.; Wister, Casper, 1818-1888
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 7 August 1835; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 23 July 1829; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Owen J. Wister, 30 September 1849; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 4 March 1830; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 23 August 1830; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Harriett Whitesides, 27 November 1827; 1.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to David Hosack, 18 July 1816; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 17 July 1830; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 26 August 1830; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to William W. Wister, 24 June 1829; 2.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865
  - ALS to Mrs. Charles Wister, 11 July 1837; 3.0 p.; Wister, Charles Jones, 1782-1865